James, Henry, 1843-1916. Henry James letters to various correspondents and other material, 1861-1915 (MS Am 1094.1): Guide.
Henry James letters to various correspondents and other material,
1861-1915.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 1094.1
James, Henry, 1843-1916.
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
Letters from Henry James acquired from multiple sources. Also includes photographs and some third party letters.
Acquired from various sources at various dates, as follows:
42M-161; 42M-163. Purchased from Austin Strong, 5 Quince St., Nantucket, Mass.; received: 1942 October 15.
43M-2. Received on exchange from Michael Papantonic, 509 Madison Ave., New York City, N.Y.; received: 1943 July 8.
43M-411F; 43M-412F; 43M-413F; 43M-414F; 43M-415F; 43M-416F. Purchased from the Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.; received: 1943 December
44M-147 Bequest of Agnes M. Storrer through Allyn B. Forbes, Esq., Massachusetts Historical Society, 1154 Boylston Street, Boston, Mass.; received: 1944 November 10.
44M-341. Purchased from Charles Retz; received: 1945 February 27.
44M-386; 44M-387. Gift (in memory of her husband Lawrence Gilman) of Elizabeth Gilman, Franconia, New Hampshire; received: 1945 June 29.
45M-57F. Purchased with funds from the Sheldon fund and a gift of Henry James, from Sir Shane Leslie, Glaslough, Co., Monaghan, Erie; received: 1945 September 25.
45M-169F. Gift of Perry G.E. Miller, Grays 18, Harvard University; received: 1946 February 14.
45M-347; 45M-348. Gift of Mrs. John W. Lapsley, through Henry James, Esq., 522 Fifth Avenue, New York, New York; received: 1946 June 26.
45M-395. Gift of Mrs. John Lapsley, through William James, Esq., 95 Irving Street, Cambridge 38, Massachusetts; received: 1946 June 10.
46M-14F. Gift of Henry James, Esq., 522 Fifth Ave., New York, New York; received: 1946 July 15.
46M-84a. Purchased from Myers & Co. with funds from the Friends of the Library.; received: 1946 December 12.
46M-89F. Purchased with funds from Henry James and the Friends fund, from Sir Shane Leslie, 35 South Lodge, St. John Wood, London, N.W. 8; received: 1947 February
46M-204. Gift of Leon Edel, Esq., 58 West 83 Street, New York 24, New York; received: 1947 March 1.
47M-4. Gift of Henry James, Esq., 522 Fifth Avenue, New York, 18 N.Y.; received: 1947 August 12.
47M-181. Bequest of Harold Wilmerding Bell; received: 1948 March 1.
49M-14; 49M-15. Gift of Leon Edel, Esq., 309 East 23d Street, New York 10, New York; received: 1949 October 4.
49M-42. Purchased with the Bemis Fund from Myers & Co., Ltd., New Bond Street, London, England; received: 1949 December 2.
49M-102. Purchased with the F.E. Chase Fund, from Ifan Kyrle Fletcher, London, England; received: 1950 Jan. 19.
50M-15; 50M-16. Gift of Mrs. Hester Ritchie Fuller, 14, Berkeley Place, Wimbledon, S.W. 19; received: 1950 September 25.
50M-427. Gift of Mrs. Henry James, 133 East 64th Street, New York 18, N.Y.; received: 1951 June.
51M-26. Purchased with Friends Fund from James F. Drake, 24 West 40th Street, New York, N.Y.; received: 1951 August 14.
51M-104. Purchased with duplicate money from Sir Shane Leslie, Bennington, Vermont; received: 1951 September 4.
51M-125. Gift of Professor Ralph Barton Perry, 985 Memorial Drive, Cambridge, Mass.; received: 1951.
51M-130 (1) - (71). Purchased with Friends fund from H.S. Fullerton, The American Hospital, Neuilly-sur-Seine, France; received: 1952 Jan. 8.
53M-32; 53M-33. Gift of Burgess Noakes, Sunnybank, Peasemarch, Sussex; via Donald Brien, Esq.; received: 1953 October 9.
53M-39. Purchased with the Bemis fund from Pickering and Chatto, 21 Suffolk Street, Pall Mall East, London S.W.1; received: 1953 October 6.
54M-66-71. Gift of William James, Esq., 95 Irving Street, Cambridge, Mass; received: 1954 July.
55M-8. Purchased with Henry James royalties from Elkin Mathews Ltd., Takeley, Bishops Stortford, Herts, England,; received: 1955 July, Cat. 140, No. 87..
56M-87; 56M-88. Gift of Mrs. Guy du Maurier, The Weavers House, Castle Combe, near Chippenham, Wiltshire; received: 1956 December 11.
57M-4
Purchased with the Bemis fund from Maggs Brothers, 50 Berkeley Square, London, W.1; received: 1957 July 10.
58M-48; 58M-49; 58M-50. Gift of Mr. Donald Brien, 220 St. Georges Road, Ardmore, Pennsylvania; received: 1958 October
58M-173. Gift of Donald Brien, 220 St. Georges Road, Ardmore, Pennsylvania; received: 1959 March 21.
58M-215. Bequest of Ellerton James, presented by direction of the executor, Mr. Sherman Hill, Hill, Barlow, Goodale & Adams, 53 State Street, Boston 9, Mass.; received: 1959 April 27.
65M-30. Gift of Mrs. H. Ryder, Cassell and Company Ltd., 35 Red Lion Square, London, W.C.1; received: 1965 August 23.
65M-130. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. F. Murray Forbes, 72 Mount Vernon Street, Boston, Mass.; received: 1966 March 1.
66M-165. Purchased partially with the Livingston fund from Miss Beatrice Dunham, 145 West 96th St., New York, N.Y. 10025 and Miss Josephine Dunham, 2 Hawthorne Place, Boston, Mass. 02114; received: 1967 June 6.
68M-54. Purchased with the Henry James royalties from Seven Gables Bookshop, 3 West 46th Street, New York, N.Y. 10036; received: 1969 May 8.
69M-148. Bequest of Miss Emma Marshall Denkinger, transmitted by Mr. Arthur W. Hughes, III, Holland, Johnson, & Hays, 73 Tremont St., Boston, Mass. 02108; received: 1969.
87M-62. Gift of Mr. David Dorrance, Saint-Vincent-de-Cosse, 24220 Saint Cyprien, France; received: 1987 November 2.
2003M-61. Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund from James Cummins Bookseller, 699 Madison Ave., New York, NY 10021; received: 2004 April 4.
2009M-61. Purchased with the Jacob Blanck Book Fund from George Houle Rare Books & Autographs; received: 2009 December 23.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
James was an American novelist, short-story writer, critic and dramatist.
Arranged into the following series:
I. Letters from Henry James to others
II. Other material
This is a collection of single letters and small groups of letters by Henry James, acquired at different times and from different sources. There are also 9 James-related photographs and a few third party letters including one letter about James dated 1952.
- I. Letters from Henry James to others
  - 2 letters to Agnes [ ],1913-1915., (1); 1 folder.
    87M-62 (4)
  - 1 card to [Thomas Bailey] Aldrich; [London],1889 Sept. 27., (2); 1 folder.
    Wrongly dated 1879 in another hand.
    46M-204
  - 1 letter to Thomas Bailey Aldrich; De Vere Gardens, [no year] Jul 27., (3); 1 folder.
    Gift of Mrs. Helen N. Roberts, 1964 Oct.
  - 2 letters to Elizabeth Asquith,1915., (4); 1 folder.
    Item 2, to "Elizabeth," possibly to Elizabeth Asquith.
    87M-62 (1)
  - 1 letter to [James] Bain; [London], [no year] May 10., (5); 1 folder.
    Directions for binding some books.
    55M-8
  - 3 letters to William W. Baldwin,1892., (6); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Venice, 1890 June 30; DeVere Gardens, 1892 Mar. 2; and DeVere Gardens, 1892 May 5.
    Mar. 2 1892 concerns the death of Alice James.
    Gift of Mrs. Henry S. Grew, 1965 Oct. 14.
  - 3 letters to Anna (Smith) Balestier,1898-1900., (7); 1 folder.
    66M-165
  - 5 letters to Anna (Smith) Balestier,1902-1911., (8); 1 folder.
  - 3 letters to Anna (Smith) Balestier,1911-1914., (9); 1 folder.
  - 2 typescript transcript copies of letters to Bay,1907-1908., (10); 1 folder.
    51M-125
  - 1 letter to Mrs. Bloomfield,1915., (11); 1 folder.
    87M-62 (2)
  - 1 letter to Chatto and Windus; Paris,[1879] Sept. 27., (12); 1 folder.
    Offering British rights to Confidence.
    53M-39
  - 1 letter to Lady Conway,1906., (13); 1 folder.
    87M-62 (3)
  - 4 letters to Alphonse Daudet,1884-1895., (14); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: London, [1884] June 19; [n.p., 1884 Sept.]; Paris, [1889] Nov. 15; and London, [1895] February 12.
    49M-14
  - 4 letters to Alphonse Daudet,1895-1896., (15); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: [ London ], [1895] Apr. 22; [ London ], 1895 June 2; [ London ], Nov. 10; and Sussex, [1896] May 15.
  - 3 letters to Alphonse Daudet,1896-1897., (16); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Sussex, [1896] July 17; [ London ], 1897 Feb. 5; and [ London], [1897] June 11.
  - 2 letters to Julie Rosalie Celeste (Allard) Daudet,1895-1897., (17); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: [ London, 1895 May]; and [London], 1897 December 31.
    49M-15
  - 4 letters to Guy du Maurier,1900., (18); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Rye, 1900 Apr. 28; Rye, [1900 Aug. 5]; Rye, 1900 Aug. 10; and Rye [1900] Aug. 15.
    56M-87 (1-4)
  - 4 letters to Guy du Maurier,1900-1915., (19); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Rye, 1900 Aug. 29; Rye, 1905 Aug. 27; Rye, 1912 Nov. 20; and [ London], 1915 Jan. 4.
    56M-87 (5-8)
  - 3 letters to Gwendolyn (Price) du Marurier,1915., (20); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: [ London ], 1915 Mar. 11; [London], 1915 Mar. 21; and [London] 1915 July. 9.
    56M-88.
  - 1 letter to Josephine Dunham,1905 May 26., (21); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Grenville T. Emmet; Rye, Sussex,1904 Jan. 9., (22); 1 folder.
    45M-348
  - 1 letter to Katharine (Temple) Emmet; Jefferson, N.H.,[1868] July 28., (23); 1 folder.
    45M-395
  - l typescript transcript letter to Isobel (Osbourne) Strong [Field]; Rye,1898 Dec. 20., (24); 1 folder.
    Apologizes for dictating a tped letter; has been confined to Rye for 6 months finishing up a pressing piece of work; was unable to see Mrs. Stevenson before her departure for Madeira with the Lloyd Osbournes; has heard indirectly of their safe arrival; hopes she and her son Austin will prosper in New York; envies her memory stored with her knowledge of R.L.S.
    42M-163
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1905 Aug. 4., (25); 1 folder.
    51M-26
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1905 Aug. 10, (26); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1905 Sept. 21, (27); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1906 Jan. 5., (28); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1906 Mar. 13., (29); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1906 Apr. 1., (30); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Paris,1907 May 3., (31); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; [Paris],1907 May 8., (32); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1907 Aug. 9., (33); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1907 Nov. 20., (34); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; [London],1907 Nov. 29., (35); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to [Horace Fletcher]; Rye,1907. Dec. 4., (36); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1908 July 22., (37); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1908 Sept 22., (38); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye,1909 Jan. 1., (39); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; [London],1909 June 2., (40); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; [London],1909 June 7., (41); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Horace Fletcher; Rye, undated., (42); 1 folder.
    Page 3 only. 51M-26
  - 17 typescript transcript letters to Mr. and Mrs. Ford Madox Ford,1896-1909., (43); 1 folder.
    With this is correspondence (originals and carbon copies) between Henry James II and Douglas Goldring, relating to a projected biography of Hueffer. 46M-14F
  - 1 letter to Thomas A. Fox; Lenox, Mass.,1911 July 8., (44); 1 folder.
    Photostat of last page and letter to T.A. Fox from Charles Eliot Norton.
    Autograph file.
  - 1 letter to Moreton Frewen; [London],1913 July 15., (45); 1 folder.
    58M-48
  - 1 letter to Moreton Frewen; [London],1914 May 6., (46); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to Hester Thackeray Fuller; [London],1915 Jan. 6., (47); 1 folder.
    Gift of Mrs. Hester R. Fuller. 50M-16
  - 1 telegram to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1890 Jan. 20., (48); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (34)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1890 Feb. 4., (49); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (37)
  - 1 unsigned telegram to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1890 May 7., (50); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (35)
  - 1 telegram (unsigned) to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1890 Sept. 5., (51); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (36)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Southport,1891 Jan. 2., (52); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (38)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [Paris],1891 Mar. 3., (53); 1 folder.
    Previously misdated as Mar. 4. Cancelled in Paris on Mar. 3, in England on Mar. 4.
    51M-130 (39)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [Paris,1891 Mar. 16]., (54); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (40)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1891 May 14., (55); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (41)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1892 Jan. 18., (56); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (42)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1892 Mar. 23., (57); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (43)
  - 1 telegram (unsigned) to William Morton Fullerton; [London,1892 Oct. 28]., (58); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (44)
  - 1 telegram to William Morton Fullerton; [Paris,1893 Apr.21]., (59); 1 folder.
    Previously misdated as Apr. 12.
    51M-130 (45)
  - 1 telegram to William Morton Fullerton; [Paris,1893 Apr. 29]., (60); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (46)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [Paris,1893 May 22]., (61); 1 folder.
    Cancelled on May 23.
    51M-130 (47)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Venice,1894 June 30., (62); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (48)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1895 Jan. 9., (63); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (49)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1895 Jan 25., (64); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (50)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1896 Jan. 5., (65); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (51)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1896 Feb. 10., (66); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (52)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,[1896] July 31., (67); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (53)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1896 Oct. 2., (68); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (55)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London,1896 Oct. no day]., (69); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (54)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1896 Dec. 19., (70); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (56)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1897 Feb 25., (71); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (57)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1897 Mar. 1., (72); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (58)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1897 Mar. 23., (73); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (59)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1897 Oct. 9., (74); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (61)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London,1897 Oct. no day]., (75); 1 folder.
    Enclosed are letters from the editor and manager of The Times.
    51M-130 (60)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, [Sussex],1898 Nov. 23., (76); 1 folder.
    Ending missing.
    51M-130 (33)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,1899 July 11., (77); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (62)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,1899 Sept. 16., (78); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (63)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,1899 Nov. 5., (79); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (64)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,1900 Jan. 27., (80); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (65)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1900 Mar. 22., (81); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (66)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,1900 Sept. 21., (82); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (67)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,1900 Sept. 26., (83); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (68)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London],1901 Mar. 12., (84); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (69)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,1901 Nov. 17., (85); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (70)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Rye, Sussex,1902 Sept. 19., (86); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (71)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [no year] Jan. 2., (87); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (9)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1893 ] Jan. 16., (88); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (10)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1893 ] Feb. 4., (89); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (11)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1893 ] Feb. 12., (90); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (12)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1896 ] Feb. 29., (91); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (13)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Genoa, [ 1894 Mar. 25]., (92); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (14)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1892 ] Mar. 4., (93); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (15)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Paris, [ 1891 ] Mar. 4., (94); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (16)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1894 ] Mar. 7., (95); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (17)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1890 ] Mar. 9., (96); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (18)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1890 ] Mar. 11., (97); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (19)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1890 ] Mar. 31., (98); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (20)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1891 ] Apr. 8., (99); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (21)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Venice, [ 1894 ] Apr. 16., (100); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (22)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1890 ] May 1., (101); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (23)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Milan, [no year] May 15., (102); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (24)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Ramsgate, [no year] July 14., (103); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (25)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Kingstown, Ireland, [no year] July 19., (104); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (26)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [no year] Sept. 6., (105); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (27)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [no year] Sept. 10., (106); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (28)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [no year] Oct. 20., (107); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (29)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [no year] Oct. 24., (108); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (30)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1890 ] Nov. 27., (109); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (31)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1894 ] Dec. 19., (110); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (32)
  - 1 telegram (unsigned) to William Morton Fullerton; Paris, [ 1893 Mar. 17]., (111); 1 folder.
    Address half of telegram only.
    51M-130 (1)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], undated., (112); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (2)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [Paris], [ 1893 ]., (113); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (3)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [Paris], [ 1893 ]., (114); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (4)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [London], [ 1896 ]., (115); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (5)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton, [ 1893 ]., (116); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (6)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; [Paris], undated., (117); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (7)
  - 1 letter to William Morton Fullerton; Ramsgate, [ 1893 June 23]., (118); 1 folder.
    51M-130 (8)
  - 1 letter to John Hays Gardiner; Rye,1899 Oct. 23., (119); 1 folder.
  - 3 letters to Constance (Lodge) Gardner,1914-1915., (120); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: [London], 1914 Apr. 9; [London], 1915 Jan. 4; and [London], 1915 Mar. 25.
  - 1 manuscript transcript portion of a letter to Edwin Lawrence Godkin, before 1915 Feb. 5., (121); 1 folder.
  - 3 letters to Sir Edmund Gosse,1896-1915., (122); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Rye, [1896] Aug. 28; Rye, 1912 Jul 12; and [ London], 1915 July 25. First page of 1915 letter is missing.
  - 1 letter to [Edmund] Gosse; Rye, Sussex,1903 Nov. 24., (123); 1 folder.
    Removed from a copy of his Notes of a son & brother, London, 1914, and included in the purchase price.
    44M-341.
  - 1 letter to [Sir Edmund] Gosse, Dover, [1884] Sept. 18., (124); 1 folder.
    57M-4.
  - 2 letters to Aline (Merriam) Harland,1905-1906., (125); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Rye, Sussex, 1905 Dec. 21; and [Rye, Sussex], 1906 Jan. 3.
    44M-386.
  - 1 letter to [Mrs. Henry] Head; Lamb House,1912 Nov. 14., (126); 1 folder.
  - 1 letter to [William] Heinemann; [London,c.1895]., (127); 1 folder.
    Concerning Henrik Ibsens, Little Eyolk, which was published in December 1894.
    47M-181.
  - 6 typescript transcript letters to Baron Von Hoffmann,1880-1881 and undated., (128); 1 folder.
  - 2 letters to Mrs. Dana Horton,1896 and undated., (129); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Rye, Sussex, [ ] May 6; and [ London], 1896 Apr. 28.
    49M- [sic].
  - 17 typescript transcript letters to Julia (Ward) Howe and Maud (Howe) Elliott,1892-1909 and undated., (130); 1 folder.
    54M-66.
  - 16 typescript transcript letters to Mrs. Ellen Hunter,1892-1915., (131); 1 folder.
    Includes two sets of these letters.
    51M-125.
  - 1 typescript transcript letter to Grenville Hunter,1903., (132); 1 folder.
    Includes two copies of this letter.
  - 1 letter to Alice Howe (Gibbens) James; Rye,[1899?], (133); 1 folder.
    54M-68 (1).
  - 1 letter to Alice Howe (Gibbens) James; Rye,1900 Jan. 31., (134); 1 folder.
    54M-68 (2).
  - 1 letter to Alice Howe (Gibbens) James; Rye,1900 Mar. 8., (135); 1 folder.
    54M-68 (3).
  - 1 letter to Alice Howe (Gibbens) James and William James; [London],1900 Mar. 17., (136); 1 folder.
    54M-70 (1).
  - 1 letter to Alice Howe (Gibbens) James and William James; Rye,[1900]., (137); 1 folder.
    54M-70 (2).
  - 1 letter to Alice Howe (Gibbens) James and William James; Rye,1910 Apr. 4., (138); 1 folder.
    54M-70 (3).
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,[1870]-1871., (139); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: 1870 June 6; Cambridge, 1870 Sept. 16; Cambridge, 1870 June 22; and Cambridge, 1871 Nov. 28.
    58M-215.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,[1881-1882]., (140); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Cambridge, [1881] Nov. 19; Cambridge, [1881] Nov. 14; Cambridge, [1882 Feb. 2]; and [ Boston, 1882 Feb. 8].
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,[1881-1882]., (141); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Boston, [1882] Feb. 10; [Boston], [1882] Feb. 20; [Boston, 1881 Nov. 30]; and [1882].
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,[1883]., (142); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: [Boston], [1883] June 15; [ Boston ], [1883] July 10; [Boston], [1883] July 14; and [Boston], [1883] July 26.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,1880-1891., (143); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: [ London ], 1880 Jan. 8 (previously misdated as 1888); Paris, 1891 Mar. 4; Paris, 1891 Mar. 24; and [London], 1891 June 8.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,[1892-1904]., (144); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: [ London, 1892] Mar. 21; [London], 1898 Apr. 3; Rye, 1898 Dec. 21; and Lenox, [1904].
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,1906-1910., (145); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Rye, 1906 Jan. 25; Rye, 1908 Nov. 26; Rye, 1908 Dec. 21; and Rye, 1910 Jan. 2.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,1910., (146); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Rye, 1910 July 29; Chocorua, 1910 Sept. 1; Cocorua, 1910 Oct. 1; and Cambridge, 1910 Oct. 29.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,1911 Mar.-May., (147); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Cambridge, 1911 Mar. 3; Cambridge, 1911 Apr. 27; Cambridge, 1911 May 10; and Cambridge, 1911 May 12.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,1911. May-July., (148); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Farmington, 1911 May 25; Salisbury, 1911 June 1; Cambridge, 1911 June 14; and Lenox, 1911 July 8.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,1911. Aug.-Dec., (149); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: Lenox, 1911 Jul 12; Rye, 1911 Aug. 12-13; [ London ] 1911 Sept. 7; and Rye, 1911 Dec. 30.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,1912-1914., (150); 1 folder.
    Includes letters: [ London ], 1912 Apr. 14; Rye, 1913 Aug. 16; [London], 1914 Apr. 10; and London, 1914 May 16.
  - 4 letters to George Abbott James,1872-1914 and undated., (151); 1 folder.